Guide to the Eugene E. Barnett Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Eugene E. Barnett Papers
1905-1970.
Barnett, Eugene E.
47.5 linear ft (ca. 59,100 items in 112 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078928
Eugene E. Barnett served as General Secretary of the Young Men's Christian Associaion (YMCA), and as the secretary of numerous committees and divisions within the YMCA in both the United States and China.
History
Eugene E. Barnett (1888-1970) began his work with the Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) by serving as a Secretary for the University of North Carolina Student YMCA from 1908-1910, where he was enrolled as a graduate student.
In 1910, the YMCA sent Barnett to China, where he was to remain until 1937. In China, he organized the YMCA in Hangchow, and served as its General Secretary until 1921. In 1925, became the Senior Secretary for the International Committee of the YMCA in China. He served concurrently as Associate General Secretary of the China National Committee and was also a member of the National Christian Council.
In 1937, the YMCA recalled Barnett to the United States, and he became the Executive Secretary of the International Board of the YMCA. In this role, he managed the World Services Program, and was instrumental in helping the YMCA to elimiate a substantial amount of accumulated debt.
In 1941, Barnett became the General Secretary of the National Council of YMCAs. He would serve in this position until his retirement in 1953.
Scope and Content
The collection includes correspondence, reports, speeches, and notes dealing with Barnett's years in pre-Communist China and in Japan, his activities as a lay leader in the Methodist Church, his many functions in the International and United States YMCA, his affiliations with several United Nations and other organizations, and his personal friends and family.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged.
Subjects
United Nations.; YMCA of the USA.; Young Men's Christian Associations of China.; Young Men's Christian Association--Japan.; China--Description and travel.; Japan--Description and travel.; Young Men's Christian associations.; Methodists.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: Boxes 2-113. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1975 M75
Gift of Arthur Doak Barnett, 1975 & 1979.
Finding aid in repository
- Series I. Cataloged Correspondence
  - Athēnagoras I, Ecumenical Patriarch of Constantinople, 1955-1964 (3 Items) (Box 1)
- Series II. Cataloged Photographs
  - Chou en lai and Eugene Epperson Barnett, 1940 (Box 1)
  - P’u Ju, Prince, circa 1937 (Box 1)
- Series III. Chronological File, 1910-1970
  (Predominantly letters to and from Barnett, but also Including some reports and speeches. The container lists includes a partial listing of the contents in the chronological Folders, arranged by year.)
  - 1910
    - Re: going to China as Y secretary - training, plans, etc. (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
      (Voyage across Pacific, first impressions of Orient, China, etc.)
  - 1911
    - First year in Hangchow (Box 1)
    - Letters home--Hangchow, Mokanshan, Robert Warren Barnett's birth, Revolution, etc. (Box 1)
    - First Annual Report (First six months in Hangchow) (Box 1)
    - Report letters and responses (Box 1)
    - Clippings (Box 1)
  - 1912
    - Letters home (Eugene Epperson Barnett) (Box 1)
    - First Christmas in own home (Box 1)
    - Reception Emperor's Island (Box 1)
    - Lantern Festival (Box 1)
    - Manchus and Republic (Box 1)
      (Manchus abdicate. Sun Ya-tsen. Yuan Shih-Kai…What’s his game?)
    - Reconstruction (Box 1)
    - Famine and Famine Relief (Box 1)
    - Student Troubles (Box 1)
    - Korean Conspiracy, etc. (Box 1)
    - Hangchow YMCA Annual Report (Box 1)
    - Report of visits to schools in area (Box 1)
    - Letter about 1911 Revolution and birth of Robert Warren Barnett (Box 1)
  - 1913
    - Letters home (mostly Eugene Epperson Barnett, one or two Bertha Smith Barnett (Mrs. Eugene Emerson Barnett)) (Box 1)
    - Civil strife (Box 1)
    - "2nd" Revolution (Box 1)
    - Korean Conspiracy (Box 1)
    - Chinese feasts (Box 1)
    - E.A. Turner (Box 1)
    - W.B. Pettus (ideas for language study) (Box 1)
    - Mokanshan.. (Box 1)
    - Temporary headquarters YMCA established (Box 1)
    - Woodrow Wilson President (Box 1)
    - Annual Report Hangchow Y (Box 1)
    - Florida Christian Advocate Eugene Epperson Barnett piece on visit to Peking, YMCA Convention (Box 1)
    - Correspondence--Henning, Brockman, Weatherford, C.T. Wang, etc. (Box 1)
  - 1914
    - Annual Report of Hangchow Y (Box 1)
    - Chu Jui (Military Governor of Chekiang ) - Gift to Y Biography. Speech February 12 (Box 1)
    - Sherwood Eddy visit (pamphlet written by H.W. Luce) (Box 1)
    - Clipping, Charlotte, N.C. paper (February 4) - letter from Eugene Epperson Barnett (Box 1)
    - Article by Eugene Epperson Barnett - "Striking Characteristics of the Modern Student" (Box 1)
    - Rubbing - Chinese text - no picture (Box 1)
    - Letters from John R. Mott, Ethan Colton, Gerald Birke, etc. (Box 1)
    - Letters home (Box 1)
    - Hangchow (Box 1)
    - Summer in Japan (Box 1)
    - Eugene Epperson Barnett invited to serve as advisor, China exhibit, Panamanian Exposition (Box 1)
    - World War (Box 1)
    - Yuan Shih-kai (Box 1)
    - C.T. Wang, S.T. Wen (Box 1)
    - Formal Opening of Hangchow Y (Box 1)
  - 1915
    - Annual Report--Hangchow Y (Box 1)
    - Report on Evangelistic meetings for Officials, Gentry, Government students, Merchants, 1914-1915 (Box 1)
    - Letter about tour of Chekiang (Forestry - D.Y. Lin accompanying Eugene Epperson Barnett) (Box 1)
    - Letters re: Y building, furlough, etc. (Box 1)
    - Letters and report from E.A.(Gene ) Turner (Buddhist priests members of Y) (Box 1)
    - Letter from Bertha Smith Barnett (Mrs. Eugene Emerson Barnett) (Box 1)
    - Letters home - Eugene Epperson Barnett (Box 1)
    - Y membership campaign (Box 1)
    - Military governor interested (Box 1)
    - Chinese New Year festival (Box 1)
  - 1916
    - Annual Report Hangchow Y (Box 2)
    - Clipping, Chinese Christian Intelligencer (?) - Tribute to H.L. Zia by Eugene Epperson Barnett (Box 2)
    - Letters re Yuan Shih Kai (May 1916); David Yui, etc. (Box 2)
    - Clipping, Florida Christian Advocate (Box 2)
    - Letters home - Eugene Epperson Barnett - (Back from furlough in U.S.) (Box 2)
  - 1917
    - Annual Report - Hangchow Y (Box 2)
    - Article: "A United Evangelistic Programme for Hanghow," by Eugene Epperson Barnett. Reprinted in? - (Paper for Hangchow Missionary Association), 1917 October (Box 2)
    - Letters to Henry G. Barnett, others - (Box 2)
    - E.A. Turner to Shanghai (Report letter) (Box 2)
    - Letters (mostly Eugene Epperson Barnett to home) (Box 2)
    - Henry DeWitt Barnett (Box 2)
    - Confucian worship (Box 2)
  - 1918
    - Annual Report Hangchow YMCA (Box 2)
    - Letters (Box 2)
    - Letter written by J.C. Oliver (Box 2)
    - Sherwood Eddy meetings - Report (Box 2)
    - Report letter - by E.A. Turner (Box 2)
    - Letters - Eugene Epperson Barnett (Box 2)
    - Hangchow (Box 2)
    - Conversations with Chinese scholars re: religion (Cross as symbol, etc.) (Box 2)
  - 1919
    - Statistical reports on Hangchow YMCA (Box 2)
    - Annual Report - Hangchow Y (Box 2)
    - Letter to Mr. (U.S. Minister) Crane and part of his address at official dinner (Box 2)
    - Letter to a Mr. Wright re: revival of Buddhism in Hangchow area (Box 2)
    - Special Correspondence to China Press (1919 October) re: (1) Hangchow student boycott of Japanese goods; (2) new business(?) and Bazaar; (3) new Governor-General, etc. (Box 2)
    - Letters to Dr. Venable, David Yui (Box 2)
    - Annual Letter to Dr. John R. Mott (Box 2)
    - Letters to Henry Barnett, parents, Fletcher Brockman, Paul Harvey, etc. with current info re: China (Box 2)
    - Letters - Eugene Epperson Barnett to family, discussing all manner of things (including reports on children) (Box 2)
  - 1920
    - Annual Report Hangchow Y (Box 2)
    - Letter report on 25th Anniversary Convention of China Y - Tientsin (Box 2)
    - "The Y.M.C.A. in China" - by Frank Rawlinson, Chinese Recorder, 1920 May (Box 2)
    - "Hangchow Young Men at Work and Play" (Pamphlet - 7th Annual Report Hangchow YMCA (Box 2)
    - Salient Facts About China by Julean Arnold, U.S. Commercial Attaché. Washington, Government Printing Office, 1920 (Box 2)
    - Photograph - Eugene Epperson Barnett and ? (Box 2)
    - Bertha Smith Barnett (Mrs. Eugene Emerson Barnett) letter re: role of Y wife in China (Box 2)
    - First Quarter Century of the Y.M.C.A. in China - D. Willard Lyon (pamphlet) (Box 2)
    - Eugene Epperson Barnett letter re: visit to Tung Yah Temple (religion predating Taoism, Confucianism, Buddhism). Night ceremonies, 1920 August 22 (Box 2)
    - Eugene Epperson Barnett letters home (Includes reports on the children) (Box 2)
    - John Dewey's 2nd visit to Hangchow (Box 2)
    - Minister and Mrs. Crane - another visit to Hangchow (Box 2)
  - 1921
    - Annual Report for 1921 Hangchow Y (in pamphlet) (Chinese and English) (Box 3)
    - Statement to Executive Committee, National Committee on Plans of Student Division for 1922 (Box 3)
    - Notes on Student Association Work in China (Box 3)
    - Family letters- to parents, Fred T. Barnett (brother of Eugene Epperson Barnett) (Box 3)
    - "Dear Friends" - Report letters, 1921 April-Midsummer (Box 3)
    - By R.R. Service - "A Running Account of Our First Twenty Years in China" (Written for theAlumni Monthly of the University of California.) (Box 3)
    - Report on Drilling of Artesian Well (Hangchow Y) Started in 1921 Report, 1925 (Box 3)
  - 1922
    - (Move to Shanghai) (Box 3)
    - Correspondence re: the move to Shanghai (Box 3)
    - Report of the Student YMCA of China for year ending September 1922 (Box 3)
    - Letter to Frank Rawlinson re: student situation (Box 3)
    - "Dear Friends" letter by George Fitch, 1922 December (Box 3)
    - Report Eddy Jones Evangelistic Campaign (Statistics) (Box 3)
    - "Dear Friends" Letter by J.C. Oliver, 1922 July (Box 3)
    - Pamphlet - Student Work of YMCA of China, based on Eugene Epperson Barnett statement April 1922 meeting of secretaries with Dr. Mott (Box 3)
    - Bulletin of Bible Union of China (Box 3)
    - Letter to Rev. Robert Howsen Barnett with article by Eugene Epperson Barnett on "The Chinese Student and the Christian Church" (Box 3)
    - The Chinese Student and Christian Church (Box 3)
    - Long letter to Eugene Epperson Barnett from R.J. McMullen on Hangchow Y problem, China Y convention, churches, Hangchow, etc. (Box 3)
    - Eugene Epperson Barnett - letters home (Box 3)
  - 1923
    - Furlough (Box 3)
    - Report of F.S. Brockman on his Trip to Far East, 1923 February-June (Box 3)
    - Pamphlet - China in 1923 (Box 3)
    - Letters from T.Z. Koo, F.S. Brockman (Box 3)
    - Memo on Eugene Epperson Barnett furlough - schedule, costs, etc. (Box 3)
    - The American Seminar in Europe, led by Kirby Page. Day by day account, 1923 Summer (Box 3)
  - 1924
    - Appointment to City Division, Shanghai - letters (Box 3)
    - Letters - Eugene Epperson Barnett to Herschleb - report (April); to F.S.Brockman; to "Dear Friends" (July 1924) re: nationalism, USSR, fellowship, conference In Hangchow and question by foreign secretaries as to their presence In China; conference with Japanese students attending - in Shanghai; to T.Z. Koo (Japanese Students in Chinese Student Conference); to F.T. Fei - Soochow, re: study of Christianity; other letters to Chinese and Japanese (including ProSakamoto, Tunghai Coll. Sh’ai); to K.Y. Ma re: Hangchow Y; to Secretaries of City Y’s re: study and discussion of Citizenship and International problems; to Rawlinson; from F.S. Brockman, T.Z. Koo. (Box 3)
    - Article in Student Bulletin (YMCA Student. Division; Sh’ai, China. Vol. VI #2 June, 1924) - by Eugene Epperson Barnett on "Summer Conferences.." (Box 3)
    - Statistics (YMCA - China) (Box 3)
    - Statement - August 1924 - American missionaries desiring that no formal military pressure be exerted to protect mission persons or property - etc. etc. (Sent to leading missionaries in China for possible signature). (Box 3)
    - Report on plans for Pan Pacific YMCA Conference to be held in Honolulu July 1925. (N.B. - The beginnings of Institute of Pacific Relations) (Box 3)
    - International Com YMCA Questionnaire for Survey 1920-1924 - Material for "Harbin, China," re: YMCA (Box 3)
  - 1925
    - "May 30th Incident" (Box 3)
      (Shooting of students in mass demonstration, Shanghai. Reports, comments, pamphlets)
    - Student Unrest in China (Box 3)
    - China - U.S. (Box 3)
      (Articles: "New Cycle in Cathay..." by John St. Burgess; "Looking at America - in China" by Lewis Gannett; "Missionaries at Caesar's Footstool" by Rawlinson)
    - Anti-Christian Movement in China (Box 3)
    - Memo of conversation of American missionaries with Strawn (and Perkins) at U.S. Consulate in Shanghai re: role of U.S. missionaries in China (Box 3)
    - Y.M.C.A. - China and Christian Movement
      - Correspondence (Box 3)
      - Copy of address by Eugene Epperson Barnett to National Christian Council (Box 3)
      - Correspondence re: Y conference, personnel changes, etc. (Box 3)
  - 1926
    - Y.M.C.A. (Box 4)
    - National Christian Council (Box 4)
    - China - Political situation, reports, magazines, etc. (Box 4)
    - Missionaries in China (Soochow Manifesto) (Box 4)
  - 1927
    - Events in Hangchow (R.J. McMullen to Eugene Epperson Barnett) (Box 4)
    - Events in Canton (Ed Lockwood) (Box 4)
    - Events in Shanghai (Ronald Reese) (Box 4)
    - Missionaries - evacuation, status, etc. (Box 4)
    - The Anti-Christian Movement (Box 4)
    - Document giving directions to Fr. Concession residents as to where to go if Shanghia evacuation necessary (actually for all foreigners in various parts of city) (Box 4)
    - T.Z. Koo in U.S.A. - Article in N.Y. Times, 1927 April 17 (Box 4)
    - Pamphlets, including both revolutionary and reactionary: "Stingy Shanghai", "Down with Shanghai Terror - Shanghai Defence Force Revolutionary Soldiers Com; "National Christian Council in China; A Bolshevik Aid Society" - Excerpts from China Daily News and Shanghai Times vs. NCC (Box 4)
    - Chiang Kai-Shek's Manifesto to the People, 1927 April (Box 4)
    - Chiang Kai-Shek's Declaration to Kuo mintang Members, 1927 April 27 (Box 4)
    - China's 25-year Struggle vs. Communism (1948 pamphlet, official) (Box 4)
    - Speech by C.Y. Cheng, D.D. - "Some Problems Confronting the Christian Movement in China" (Box 4)
    - R.J. McMullen - on why some missionaries did not evacuate (Hangchow in particular) when othars felt it necessary etc. (Box 4)
    - China - Political and Military Events (Box 4)
    - Nanking Incident (Box 4)
    - International relations (U.S. and British policies) (Box 4)
    - Soviets in China (Canton, Borodin, etc.) (Box 4)
    - YMCA - Aftermath of Nanking Incident and Anti-foreignism (Box 4)
    - Mid-May Reflecions (a report on China - Eugene Epperson Barnett) (Box 4)
    - Other reports (Box 4)
    - Communism in Y - Declaration of Workers in Foreign Institutions (Box 4)
    - YMCA Secretary (Eugene Epperson Barnett) - Salary, Cost of living estimate for Shanghai for 1928 (Box 4)
  - 1928
    - Observations- Yangtze Valley (Box 4)
    - YMCA reports, letters (Box 4)
    - Conference on Island of Pootoo - pictures, etc. (Box 4)
    - Report letter - Eugene Epperson Barnett (Box 4)
      (Situation in China and Y)
    - Other Y reports (Box 4)
      (Conference in Shanghai in September, 1928)
    - Notes on Kaifeng, 1928 December (Box 4)
    - Communism in South China (Box 4)
    - Report letter, 1928 May (Box 4)
    - Shanghai College report (Box 4)
    - Feng Yu-hsiang (Box 4)
    - Tsinen Incident, 1928 May (Box 4)
    - University of Nanking Report, 1928 April (Box 4)
    - North China Monthly Trade Report (Box 4)
    - Other report letters, speeches; Missionary future discussed (Box 4)
  - 1929
    - Correspondence re: Eugene Epperson Barnett family furlough and trip to U.S. via Europe, 1929 Summer (Box 5)
    - Report (by Eugene Epperson Barnett) on Impressions of the Church in China, 1929 February (Box 5)
    - Report on Church in China in Chinese Recorder (see above), 1929 April (Box 5)
    - Reports on City Associations of China for 1927 (Box 5)
    - Report of Shanghai Y Conference, 1929 May (Box 5)
    - Series of lettess (June, September, etc.) from Frank Rawlinson on Cnina and Christianity in China (Box 5)
    - Reports on political developments - China - by T.Z.Koo, 1929 Fall (Box 5)
    - Documents with Reference to the Sino-Russian Dispute, 1929 (Box 5)
      (Published by F.E. Information Bureau, Nanking. Gift of C.T. Wang)
    - Pamphlet - Dr. David Yui - China and Pacific Relations During 1927-29 (Address - IPR - Kyoto Conference) (Box 5)
    - Foreign Policy Association Information Service, 1929 October 30 (Box 5)
    - Article in Richmond Times-Dispatch by Major-General Smedley D. Butler, U.S. Marines (Box 5)
    - Eugene Epperson Barnett's Trans-Siberian Journey (Box 5)
    - Furlough (Box 5)
    - Fall-Winter (Box 5)
    - Family letters (Box 5)
      (Eugene Epperson Barnett to Bertha Smith Barnett (Mrs. Eugene Emerson Barnett), RB and Eugenia Mae Barnett in college, etc.)
  - 1920s-1930s
    - Folder on Anti-Christian Movement in China
      - Pamphlets (Box 5)
      - Speeches (Box 5)
      - Discussions (Box 5)
      - Questionnaires (Box 5)
  - 1930
    - Return of Eugene Epperson Barnett to China after furlough (Box 5)
    - Agenda for October 21-December 5 (Box 5)
    - Report (conwith Mr. Gerald Birks), 1930 December 17 (Box 5)
    - Report on General Situation - China (David Yui) (Chiang Kai-shek's baptism) (Box 5)
    - Report: YMCA Personnel, etc. (Box 5)
    - Letter-Report - Cowles Family trip home via Siberia, Europe, 1930 Summer (Box 5)
    - YMCA reports and letters (Box 5)
    - Re: Survey of YM and YW in China (Dr. E.M. Best) (Box 5)
    - Eugene Epperson Barnett Family Letters
      - In US to May 31 (Box 5)
      - Enroute to Shanghai (Box 5)
      - Trip with Fong Sec to Canton to secure release of S. Cheng (Other subjects - e.g. Communism) (Box 5)
      - Financial report China Y toCharles Herschleb (Box 5)
      - A few letters to Eugene Epperson Barnett (Box 5)
      - China, 1930 June-December
        - Summer alone in Shanghai (Box 5)
        - Reunited (Bertha Smith Barnett (Mrs. Eugene Emerson Barnett), DeWitt, Doak back), 1930 October-December (Box 5)
        - Especially interesting - Political situation; Yen Hsi-shan, Feng Yu-hsiang; Nanking; Ginling Coll.;Dr. Wu Yi-fang - others (Miss Kan, former Hangchow kindergarten teacher -later married Lawrence Liu}; "Squeeze" in China, etc. (Box 5)
  - 1931
    - Family Letters, Subjects Include:
      - Yangtse River Constitution (?) (Box 6)
      - Cuts in Y Staff, 1931 March 11 (Box 6)
      - Christians in Nanking Government (Box 6)
      - Feud in Nanchang - Meth. Ch. (Box 6)
      - Stopping Communism with bullets, 1931 April 16 (Box 6)
      - Communists in Changsha, 1931 April 30 (Box 6)
      - Idealism and Terrorism of Communists, 1931 May 6 (Box 6)
      - Depression (?) in Pacific, 1931 July 9 (Box 6)
      - Soong Family, 1931 July 9 (Box 6)
      - China's plight - flood October 10th etc. (Box 6)
  - 1931-1932
    - September 18th Manchurian Incident, 1931 (Box 6)
    - Reports by: Helde, Sherwood Eddy, T.Z. Koo, S.C. Leung, 1930-1931 (Box 6)
    - China -"Y" (Miscellaneous notes on Y In China. "Historical Sketch of Y's in China" -printed excerpt), 1931 (Box 6)
    - Family letters (references to Soongs, Chiang), 1931 (Box 6)
    - Non-Eugene Epperson Barnett - Japanese militaristic policy and actions, 1931-1933 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence re: call of Eugene Epperson Barnett to N.Y. (International Com. Y.), 1931 (Box 6)
    - Shanghai Incident, 1932 (Box 7)
    - Reaction to "Shanghai Incident" - Christian churches (Box 7)
    - Personal letters re: Japan's aggression (Box 7)
    - Maps (Box 7)
  - 1932
    (Predominantly family letters)
    - To Robert Warren Barnett and Eugenia Mae Barnett re: college problems, finances, after college, etc. (Box 7)
    - References to current events and other topics listed on cover of Folder, including:
      - Lytton Commission (Box 7)
      - National Conference of Y Secretaries (Box 7)
      - Mussolini's speech (Box 7)
      - Conditions in China, Manchuria, Japan (in letter to Robert Warren Barnett of November 4th ) (Box 7)
      - Visit to Headquarters 19th Route Army on November 27th, etc. etc. (Box 7)
  - 1933
    - Mostly Y in China (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous: Obituary on Henry Hodgkin - Chinese Recorder; Latter to Frank Rawlinson; Memo on Remarks of Nelson T. Johnson; Report on F.E, and Indian Area Y Conference; Other Y material. (Box 7)
    - Family Letters (Box 7)
      (Topics listed on Folder)
  - 1934
    - Reports on Y's in China (visits to various areas) (Box 8)
    - Hangchow Y report (Box 8)
    - Article on Beginnings of Hangchow Y in Tung Kung, (?) by Eugene Epperson Barnett (Box 8)
    - Pamphlet on New Life Movement by Chiang Kai-shek, translated by Mme. Chiang (Box 8)
    - Family Letters (Box 8)
      (Including: from Henry DeWitt Barnett, ADS, Robert Warren Barnett (M.A. Chapel Hill, North Carolina - coming out to Shanghai enroute Oxford University); re: summer family reunion; Eugene Epperson Barnett to PHB - letters, etc.)
  - 1935
    - Eugene Epperson Barnett - 25th Anniversary of service in China (Ivory seal inscription) (Box 8)
    - Social affairs of note
      - Discussion group meeting at Eugene Epperson Barnett's (Henry Luce present) (Box 8)
      - H.H. Kung reception for Vice President Garner, etc. (Box 8)
    - Memos on situation in China - on visit to Wuchang, Nanchang, Hankow, Changsha, 1935 May (Box 8)
    - Letters referring to Manchuria (Box 8)
    - Review of Fletcher S. Brockman’s book (I Discover the Orient) (Box 8)
    - Personnel data on China Y Secretaries (Box 8)
    - Fellowship Notes (Box 8)
      (Review of work of Y in China 1835-1935)
    - Y pamphlet (Box 8)
    - Family Letters (Box 8)
      (To Robert Warren Barnett (Oxford, Europe); Eugenia Mae Barnett (Peking); Henry DeWitt Barnett (Webb School, California). Subjects: Japan, Communism in China, (the) Depression, the Raven trial, R.R. Service's Illness and death, Dr, David Yui's illness, etc...)
    - Non-Eugene Epperson Barnett
      - Reports on Manchuria (Box 8)
      - Address by Wang Ching-Wei (Premier of China) in Nanking conference, 1935 June (Box 8)
      - Announcement of lectures on Chinese Culture sponsored by Y. (Box 8)
      - Statement by L.T. Chen re: China and Y. (Box 8)
  - 1936
    - Family Letters (Box 8)
      (Subjects include: Death of Dr. David Yui; Death of Eugene Epperson Barnett’s father, the Rev. Robert H. Barnett; and 1936 "Forebodings" regarding Henry DeWitt Barnett, Franklin Delano Roosevelt, New Age and Totalitarianism, Visit to Hangchow, Chinese soldiers, and the "New Deal" )
    - Speeches--Eugene Epperson Barnett (Box 8)
      (Including "China Goes Modern", "Supercargo" - What the West has given to China - cultural end scientific, education, medical science, athletics, Relief work, "Awakened China")
  - 1937
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9)